{LP} LEE POWELL

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

♥ WEM, SY4 5BL

\(07815 051269

DETAILS

84 Station Road Wem, SY4 5BL 07815051269 Leeap83@gmail.com

LINKS

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/leepowell83

Portfolio: https://leeap83.co.uk/

SKILLS

HTML & CSS
Python
Django
JavaScript
jQuery
Git
SQL & MySQL
PostgreSQL
Bootstrap 4/Materialize
MongoDB
Microsoft Office
Bookkeeping
Customer Service
Database Management
Figma – UX Design

STRENGTHS

Attention to Detail
Problem Solving
Creative Thinking
Patience & Self Direction
Adaptability
Organised



PROFILE

A **resourceful** and **conscientious** professional individual who has experience working in finance and customer advisor roles. After a career change and completion of a Full Stack Web Developer diploma is now working as a Web Developer.

Proficient in HTML5, CSS, Python, has a passion for Front-End Development and has strong skills and experience in Database Management.

Understands the importance and principles of good UX/UI design and user experience. Utilises CSS frameworks such as Bootstrap and Materialize for developing responsive and mobile-first designs.



ACHIEVEMENTS

- Completed Full Stack Web Developer Diploma from The Code Institute
- Cleansed and implemented an updated Practice Management software to manage 6500+ clients' accounts for large accountancy practice.
- Controlled sales ledgers and recovered debt of up to £1 million on monthly basis.
- Implemented **new workflow** automation to improve efficiency in finance team.
- Organised two large scale **charitable events**, raising over **£10,000** for 2 charities.



EXAMPLES OF MY WORK

- <u>Lee's Burger Kitchen</u> A Full Stack food ordering site built using HTML5, CSS
 JavaScript, Django, Heroku & PostgreSQL. View code on <u>GitHub</u> page.
- Movie Review A movie review site to showcase Back-End development using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Flask and MongoDB. View code on <u>GitHub</u> page.
- Where's Next? A Interactive Front-End application that utilises Google Maps to allow the user to find their next holiday destination using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Google Maps API View code on GitHub page.
- PalletOnline
 - https://palletonline.co.uk/status
 - https://palletonline.co.uk/direct/
 - https://palletonline.co.uk/shop



CURRENT EMPLOYMENT

Junior Web Developer at PalletOnline (Brown's Distribution), Stoke October 2021 – Present

Creating and updating webpages for the PalletOnline website, based on wireframes created by the marketing team. Ensuring that they are user friendly and adhere to the principles of good UX design, whilst always ensuring that the brand stays consistent throughout the site.

Using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP to create mobile first responsive webpages and improving user experience. Updating the user account section to ensure its practical and easy to navigate

Utilising Git for version control and optimizing SEO performance, speed and scalability using SEMrush to check and resolve any issues found.

Creating branded booking confirmation email templates using HTML and CSS.

INTERESTS

Sports, Hiking, Cooking, Coding

VOLUNTEERING & CHARITY

St John's Ambulance 2011 – 2012

Volunteered at St John's Ambulance after completing a first aid at work certificate

3 Peaks Challenge

August 2017

Organised and participated in raising over £7,000 for Kidney Research

Charity Football Match May 2014

Organised and participated in raising over £3,000 for Severn Hospice



EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Finance Administrator at Whittingham Riddell Chartered Accountants, Shrewsbury May 2007 – October 2020

Working in the accounts team for thirteen years for a large accountancy and business advisory practice, providing support to the firm's accounting function through a varied role, including credit control, sales ledger management, development of the practice management software, financial reporting, and maintenance of the client database.



July 2005 - March 2007

Working as a Customer Advisor for M&S in the Food Hall in a number of stores in the West Midlands, dealing with customers and complaints, assisting in the opening of new stores in the region, training new staff, overseeing the grocery department in one of the new stores, analyzing stock reports and displaying stock/merchandise to improve sales.

Mess Hand at RAF Shawbury, Shrewsbury

July 1998 - September 2002

Working on the RAF Base in the Mess as a Mess hand/steward, dealing with food preparation, waiting on and cleaning.



EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Diploma at the Code Institute

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Python | Django | MongoDB | Flask | MySQL 2020 – 2021 – Merit

BA Hons Film & Media Studies at University of Central Lancashire, Preston $2002-2005-2:2\ \text{Grade}$

A-Levels at Thomas Adams College, Wem

2000 - 2002 - Film Studies (B), Media Studies (C), Psychology (D)

GNVQ Business Studies at Thomas Adams College, Wem

1999 - 2000 - Merit Grade

GCSE at Thomas Adams School, Wem

1994 – 1999 – Including Maths, Science & English (C)

REFERENCES

Upon Request